Guide to Miscellaneous Financial Materials Concerning Natural Gas Companies Operating in the North American West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miscellaneous financial materials concerning natural gas companies operating in the North American West
1895-1957
Ndy53
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.55
(17 boxes)
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning natural gas companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, company profiles and newsletters, consumer information, maps, reprints of newspaper articles, journal articles, obituaries, statements and addresses of company officers, letters and notices to the stockholders, reports, balance sheets, prospectuses, bond and debenture selling agreements, subscription agreements, proxy statements, stock and bond offerings, mortgage and trust indentures, and plans and agreements of re-organization. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of these financial materials were part of a collection acquired by Yale in 1922 from William H. Brown of West Haven, Conn. The collection, initially called the William H. Brown Statistical Library, numbered some 23,000 documents and covered the years 1890 to 1917. The collection was merged with similar materials already in the University Library and later expanded by gifts from Brown and others to become what is now known as the William H. Brown Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning natural gas companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence, company profiles and newsletters, consumer information, maps, reprints of newspaper articles, journal articles, obituaries, statements and addresses of company officers, letters and notices to the stockholders, reports, balance sheets, prospectuses, bond and debenture selling agreements, subscription agreements, proxy statements, stock and bond offerings, mortgage and trust indentures, and plans and agreements of re-organization. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically by company name.
Gas companies -- West (U.S.); Trust indentures -- Specimens.; Proxy statements -- Specimens.; Financial statements -- Specimens.; Denver Gas and Electric Company; William H. Brown Collection
- California Gas and Electric Corporation, 1907; Ndy53 U2 +C13; (6 documents) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Capital Gas and Electric Company, 1924; Ndy53 U2 +C172; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Colorado Springs Light, Heat and Power Company, 1910-1925; Ndy53 U2 +C71; (8 documents) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Continental Gas and Electric Corporation, 1912-1928; Ndy53 U2 +C82; (14 documents) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- County Gas Company (of Texas), 1926; Ndy53 U2 +C84; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Dallas Gas Company, 1905-1921; Ndy53 U2 +D16; (3 documents) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Denver Gas and Electric Company, 1903-1925; Ndy53 U2 +D42; (3 documents) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Denver Gas and Electric Light Company, 1911-1921; Ndy53 U2 +D43; (4 documents) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Dixie Gas and Utilities Company, 1929; Ndy53 U2 +D643; (1 document) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- El Paso Natural Gas Company, 1936-1957; Ndy53 U2 +El69; (3 documents) (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Gas Securities Company, 1913-1920; Ndy53 U2 +G21; (4 documents) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Houston Gas and Fuel Company, 1912; Ndy53 U2 +H81; (1 document) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Houston Gulf Gas Company, 1926-1928; Ndy53 U2 +H82; (6 documents) (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
- Interstate Natural Gas Company, Incorporated, 1926; Ndy53 U2 +In8; (3 documents) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Iowa Electric Company, 1914; Ndy53 U2 +Io85; (2 documents) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Kansas City Gas Company, 1897-1922; Ndy53 U2 +K105; (3 documents) (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
- Kansas Gas and Electric Company, 1910-1949; Ndy53 U2 +K11; (12 documents) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Kansas Power and Light Company, 1925-1939; Ndy53 U2 +K14; (3 documents) (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
- Lone Star Gas Corporation, 1927-1938; Ndy53 U2 +L841; (3 documents) (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
- Los Angeles Gas and Electric Corporation, 1909-1937; Ndy53 U2 +L89; (17 documents) (Box 14, Folder 1-3)
- Louisiana Gas Company, 1928; Ndy53 U2 +L92; (1 document) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Midway Gas Company, 1915-1920; Ndy53 U2 +M58; (2 documents) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Minneapolis Gas Light Company, 1896-1924; Ndy53 U2 +M666; (5 documents) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Missouri Gas Company of Kansas City, Mo., 1895; Ndy53 U2 +M692; (1 document) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Montana-Dakota Power Company, 1926-1927; Ndy53 U2 +M76; (2 documents) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Northwestern Utilities, Limited, 1923; Ndy53 U2 +N82; (2 documents) (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Northwest Cities Gas Company, 1929; Ndy53 U2 +N86; (1 document) (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Oklahoma Gas and Electric Company, 1902-1936; Ndy53 U2 +Ok3; (14 documents) (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
- Oklahoma Natural Gas Company, 1919-1936; Ndy53 U2 +Ok4; (7 documents) (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Oklahoma Natural Gas Corporation, 1926-1929; Ndy53 U2 +Ok5; (10 documents)
  - 1 document (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 9 documents (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
- Oklahoma Northern Gas Company, 1927; Ndy53 U2 +Ok6; (1 document) (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Pacific Gas and Electric Company, 1909-1951; Ndy53 U2 +P11; (109 documents)
  - 1 document (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - 13 documents (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
  - 73 documents (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
  - 22 documents (Box 16, Folder 3-5)
- Pacific Lighting Corporation, 1928-1951; Ndy53 U2 +P14; (14 documents) (Box 16, Folder 6-7)
- Palmer Corporation of Louisiana, 1928; Ndy53 U2 +P18; (1 document) (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Portland Gas and Coke Company, 1909-1921; Ndy53 U2 +P83; (3 documents) (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Republic Gas Corporation, 1932; Ndy53 U2 +R29; (1 document) (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Rio Grande Valley Gas Company, 1927-1935; Ndy53 U2 +R477; (6 documents) (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
- St. Louis County Gas Company, 1912; Ndy53 U2 +Sa15; (3 documents) (Box 9, Folder 4)
- St. Louis Gas and Coke Corporation, 1927-1935; Ndy53 U2 +Sa17; (2 documents) (Box 9, Folder 5)
- St. Paul Gas Light Company, 1899-1924; Ndy53 U2 +Sa2; (7 documents) (Box 10, Folder 1)
- San Diego Consolidated Gas and Electric Company, 1909-1935; Ndy53 U2 +Sa5; (9 documents) (Box 17, Folder 3)
- San Francisco Gas and Electric Company, 1903-1911; Ndy53 U2 +Sa6; (3 documents) (Box 17, Folder 4-6)
- San Joaquin Light and Power Corporation, 1910-1927; Ndy53 U2 +Sa8; (12 documents) (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
- Seattle Lighting Company, 1904-1926; Ndy53 U2 +Se2; (3 documents) (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Sioux Falls Gas Company, 1924; Ndy53 U2 +Si7; (3 documents) (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Southern California Gas Company, 1910-1943; Ndy53 U2 +So8; (15 documents) (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Southern Counties Gas Company of California, 1911-1937; Ndy53 U2 +So83; (6 documents) (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Southern Gas Company, 1924-1936; Ndy53 U2 +So88; (3 documents) (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Southern United Gas Company, 1927; Ndy53 U2 +So94; (3 documents) (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Southwest Gas Company, 1927; Ndy53 U2 +So95; (3 documents) (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Union Gas Corporation, 1926; Ndy53 U2 +Un25; (2 documents) (Box 12, Folder 1)
- United Gas Company, 1928-1930; Ndy53 U2 +Un67; (6 documents) (Box 12, Folder 2)
- United Gas Corporation, 1930-1944; Ndy53 U2 +Un68; (8 documents) (Box 12, Folder 3)
- United Gas Public Service Company, 1931; Ndy53 U2 +Un75; (1 document) (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Washington Gas Light Company, 1941; Ndy53 U2 +W27; (2 documents) (Box 12, Folder 5)